Wenn es um jüdische Geschichte und Rückkehr geht: Wie verstehst Du deine jüdische und israelische
Identität?
It’s funny to say "the people from Europe",
because firstly, there were people here,
my family was here.
About 20 generations
I counted already, about 20 generations.
So my family was here...
Jews were not parachuted into the Middle East.
Me myself for example
I'm a huge mixture of Middle East,
I have Yemenite roots and Libyan...
Moroccan and Israeli...
From this region...
And...
My husband for example,
his parents are from Tunisia and Egypt and...
If you take my children today,
you see this mix of ethnicities,
where should we go?
it’s so funny,
that...
people around the world say
"The UN gave Israel ..."
or "the British gave Israel to the Jews",
or "the Balfour Declaration".
but what gave us the land of Israel
Now listen, all of those are really nice things,
is winning the wars against our neighbors,
which we paid a lot of blood for.
So that what, end of the day
because you can recognize a country,
people are now recognizing the Palestinian state.
Is it here?
You need to fight for your place.
That's what we did, that's what we did.
That's what gave us
the right to stay here,
because otherwise
we would have just ended up like the Yezidis
or the Copts...
or the Kurds.